Arjun Naik October 29, 1987

Arjun.RN@gmail.com • +49-176-5788-6406

https://de.linkedin.com/in/arnaik
 https://github.com/arjunrn

Berliner Allee 148 • 13088 • Berlin • Germany

Summary

commerce and foundational systems. Has a passion for mid-level engineers. Looking for positions in teams buildbuilding features and functionality with a focus on reliabil- ing critical systems with high performance, reliability reity, scalability and maintainability. Established record of quirements like security, infrastructure.

Software engineer with 10+ years of experience in e- collaboration on large projects, mentorship of junior and

Experience

Delivery Hero

BERLIN, GERMANY Aug 2022 - Current

Staff Software Engineer - Global Developer Platform

Developed a cluster lifecycle and fleet management solutions for the new Global Developer Platform. Maintainence and steering of the self-service deployment tooling for users of the platform. contributions to upstream AWS projects for managing AWS resources through Kubernetes resources. Mentoring of engineers, design of systems in the domain and collaboration with other domains and entities.

Technologies Used: Go, Kubernetes, AWS controllers for Kubernetes, Open Application Model.

Red Hat

BERLIN, GERMANY

Senior Software Engineer OpenShift

Jun 2021 - Jul 2022

Developement of operators to extend the functionality of the OpenShift Container Platform through CRDs and controllers. Adding new features to the core OpenShift platform in the areas of networking and authentication and cluster upgrades.

Technologies Used: Go, OpenShift, controller-runtime, kubebuilder

Red Hat

BERLIN, GERMANY

Senior Software Engineer SRE

Iul 2020 - May 2021

Development and standardization of operators used to managed Openshift Dedicated clusters. Improving the monitoring of features used in OSD clusters.

Technologies Used: Go, OpenShift, Prometheus, controller-runtime, kubebuilder

Zalando SE

BERLIN, GERMANY

Senior Software Engineer (AWS and Kubernetes)

Aug 2018 - June 2020

Provided Kubernetes clusters and CI/CD integration to feature teams in Zalando to deploy their applications. Monitoring and upgrading the clusters so that teams can benefit from improved security and reliability. Development of internal and opensource tooling for cluster users to deploy their applications seamlessly and perform application deployments with advanced features like pre-scaling, blue-green deployments and easy rollbacks. Improved autoscaling controllers in upstream Kubernetes projects so that user workloads can scale both vertically and horizontally. Other contributions to upstream Kubernetes open source projects.

Technologies Used: AWS, Go, Kubernetes, Ubuntu.

Cubits

BERLIN, GERMANY

Site Reliability Engineer

Jan 2018 - May 2018

Migration of the stack from baremetal to GKE clusters. Modified existing services to run on Kubernetes **Technologies Used:** Google Compute Platform, Terraform, Helm, Prometheus.

Zalando SE

BERLIN, GERMANY

Software Engineer SRE

August 2015 - December 2017

Part of the SRE team which worked with the feature teams in the migration of a monolithic codebase to microservices in the cloud. During this process of migration assisted teams in automating their deployments, instrumenting their applications for monitoring and performed load test to verify that the newly built services could satisy the performance and scaling requirements. Later moved to the Personalization department where I worked with the Recommendations team to deliver personalized item recommendations with Service Level Objectives(SLOs). Automating the deployments of the their infrastructure and implemented controllers and tooling to manage their datastores like Elasticsearch and Cassandra. Introduced monitoring for visualizing and observing the performance of various stages of the recommendations pipeline.

Technologies Used: Go, Java, AWS, locust, Spring Boot, Kubernetes, Elasticsearch, Cassandra.

TU Dresden

Dresden, Germany

Wissenschaftliche Hilfskraft

Mar 2014 - Dec 2014

As a part of the SREX(Secure Remote Execution) project developed a translator for C programs which added redundancy to regular x86 instructions to detect and correct transient errors in memory and computation. Also worked with consensus services like ZooKeeper and Consul to evalute their runtime characteristics. Implemented several new prototype features for a ZooKeeper client library.

Technologies Used: Python, Fabric, Apache ZooKeeper, C/C++, Scons, Consul, Mercurial

DMFS Application Developer

Dresden, Germany

Jan 2013 - March 2014

Developed a web based platform for the bulk retail of mobile apps. The service used OpenSSL to sign packaged apps and verified the source of the app sold through the platform. Also developed the Android SDK which integrates with existing third-party apps to leverage this functionality. This also included the task of building and maintaining the infrasturcture for deploying and running the platform.

Technologies Used: Python, Android, Django, OpenSSL, PostgreSQL, Git

Locus Labs Bangalore, India

Web and Mobile Developer

Jun 2011 - August 2012

Locus Labs was an early stage startup for providing location based advertising and services through mobile applications. Had to manage several resposibilities, from building the backend services, tinkering with the frontend code and also maintaing the deployment pipelines to make releases.

Technologies Used: Django, Python, Android, Tornado, Fabric, Scrapy, Javascript, JQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Git

Netbramha Studios

Bangalore, India

Web Developer

Oct 2010 - May 2011

Netbramha Studios is a design consultancy which develops aesthetic and content intensive websites. Handled the technical aspects list aaintenance of websites and minor front-end development. Also built websites using both third-party and in-house server frameworks. Used JQuery for front-end development and also did some basic layout and styling with HTML+CSS.

Technologies Used: PHP, CodeIgniter, CakePHP, JQuery, Javascript, Python, Django, SVN, Git

Please consult my LinkedIn Profile for references.

Education

Techniche Universität Dresden

Dresden, Germany

Master of Science, Distributed Systems Engineering

Oct 2012 – Mar 2015

Completed courses in Security and Cryptography, Software Fault Tolerance and Dependable Systems. Also worked in the Systems Engineering Lab and Software Fault Tolerance Lab. Under the guidance of Prof. Dr. Christof Fetzer completed my Master's Thesis in scaling Zookeeper. The thesis proposed a solution which partitioned the Zookeeper FS namespace to shard the data and increase the throughput by reducing the overhead of the consensus algorithm.

BM Sreenivasaiah College of Engineering, Vivesvararya Technological University Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering

Bangalore, India Jul 2006 – Apr 2010

Major in Computer Science with a focus on Computer Architecture. Was also an editor of the departmental newsletter and a regular contributor. For my final year project developed a Wi-Fi enabled robot which could be controlled over the Internet.

Skills

Technical Skills: Software design and architecture, Linux internals(particularly containers and networking), databases, REST APIs. Proficient in Go and Python with some background in Java and C/C++.